+44 7719460212 London, UK

# Chun Hei (Samuel) Lam

Statistician

chun.lam18@imperial.ac.uk Website: samuel-chlam.github.io

I am a final year undergraduate at Imperial College London. I was selected as a candidate for the MIT-Imperial exchange programme. My main research interests are random matrix theory and its applications to statistical learning. In my spare time, I also research on dynamical systems and stochastic analysis.

#### **EDUCATION**

# MSci Mathematics with a Year Abroad

October 2018 — Present

Imperial College London, London, UK

Year 1: 89.47/100, Year 2: 87.49/100

Dean's list candidate for year 1 and year 2

# MIT-Imperial Exchange Programme

September 2020 — June 2021

Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MA

Year 3: GPA 5.0/5.0

- · As part of MSci Mathematics with a Year Abroad
- · Indicative course content: Random Matrices, Non-Asymptotic Statistics, Stochastic Analysis, Bayesian Inference

### A Level, General Certificate of Education

September 2016 — June 2018

HKCCCU Logos Academy, Hong Kong

· A\* in Mathematics, Further Mathematics, Further Mathematics (Additional) and Chinese, A in Physics

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

# Professor Alastair Young's Group

October 2021 — Present

Imperial College London, London, UK

- · Project: Equivalence between density estimation and nonparametric regression.
- · Master Thesis for MSci Mathematics with a Year Abroad
- The project studies the Le Cam's characterisation of equivalence between density estimation and nonparametric regression. We study the meaning of equivalence for the estimation problems.

Muller Lab July 2021 — Present

Western University, Ontario, Canada

- · Part of the Fields Undergraduate Summer Research Programme (FUSRP)
- · Project: Spectrum of Almost Complete Graph
- · We studied the spectra of Almost Complete Graphs (ACG), which are complete graphs with a small number of edges removed. Further applications on Echo-State Networks have also been studied.
- · Journal paper under preparation.

# Professor Leonid Kogan's Group

January 2021 — June 2021

Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MA

- · Part of the Undergraduate Research Opportunities Programme (UROP)
- Project: Classification of Financial Time Series
- · We developed some methods of simulating financial time series simulation compared algorithms of distinguishing simulated time series from real-life data.

# Dr. Michele Coti-Zelati's Group

June 2020 — September 2020

Imperial College London, London, UK

- · Part of the Undergraduate Research Opportunities Programme (UROP)
- · Project: Enhanced Diffusion Equation
- We studied how the  $\ell^2$  energy of solutions of enhanced diffusion equations decay with time using mathematical analysis and numerical simulation in Python. A directed reading on stochastic analysis then followed.

Last updated: May 12, 2022

Dr. Andrew Duncan's Group June 2019

Imperial College London, London, UK

- · Part of Year 2 Mathematics Group Project
- · Project: A Retrospective Analysis of Governmental Interventions to Covid-19
- · We developed new Bayesian models on the reproduction numbers of Covid-19 and used them to evaluate the effectiveness of various governmental interventions with R and STAN.

Dr. Andrew Duncan's Group June 2018

Imperial College London, London, UK

- · Part of first-year Mathematics Individual Poster Project
- · Project: Simple Application of Approximate Bayesian Computation in Modelling Tumor Growth
- · We investigated the application of rejection sampling and the Metropolis-Hasting algorithm in estimating the growth rate of tumours in an experiment using Matlab.
- Outstanding poster project (scored 98/100)

#### **ACTIVITIES**

Webmaster August 2021 — Present

Imperial College Mathematics Society

- · Redesigned the promotional website of the society: https://rcsu.gitlab.io/icl-mathsoc/newsite/
- · Currently initiating a repository of student-written course materials and expository writings to facilitate discussions and revisions.

Peer Tutor October 2020 — April 2021

Imperial College London

- · Hosting weekly tutorials to facilitate first-year students' studies and provide them with overviews of more advanced topics in mathematics and statistics.
- · Syllabus available on my personal website.

## **AWARDS**

Selected as the candidate for MIT-Imperial Exchange Programme.

2020

Dean's List for year 1 and year 2. (Top 10% of the year)

2019, 2020

**SKILLS** 

Scientific Computation Python, Julia, Matlab, R, STAN, Git

Webpage Development Javascript (with React.js and Node.js), HTML5/CSS3

**Communication** English, Cantonese (Native), Chinese (Native, reading and writing)

Last updated: May 12, 2022